THE JUDGE RETURNS
판사가 돌아오다
SHIN NAM-SUK
신남석
But if you still insist that you were fair
하지만 당신이 여전히 공정하다고 주장한다면
look at me straight in the eyes and tell me.
내 눈을 똑바로 봐 그리고 말해 보세요.
"Mother"
"어머니"
"I made a fair judgment."
"나는 공정한 판단을 내렸다."
"I'm a judge of justice."
"나는 정의의 판사다."
Then, I'll believe you, no matter what, okay?
그럼, 당신을 믿을게요. 무슨 일이 있어도, 알았지?
I was very fair in court.
나는 법정에서 매우 공정했습니다.
I'm a judge of justice.
나는 정의의 판사입니다.
I know it's too late
너무 늦었다는 걸 알아
but...
하지만...
you'll be on my side, right, Mom?
당신은 내 편이 되어줄 거예요, 그렇죠, 엄마?
SUPREME COURT
대법원
EPISODE 2
에피소드 2
Where's Chairman Jang?
장 회장은 어디 계시나요?
He should be with his attorney right now.
그는 지금 당장 변호사와 함께 있어야 합니다.
- Is that so? - Yes.
- 그렇습니까? - 예.
How is it?
어때요?
How's the food there?
거기 음식은 어때요?
I'll just think of this as a little holiday
이것만 생각해볼게 약간의 휴일로
but won't the Haenal Partner's daughter be disappointed?
하지만 해날파트너의 딸은 그렇지 않겠죠? 실망하다?
Seriously.
진지하게.
Why would you act so out of character?
왜 그렇게 성격이 나쁜 행동을 하시나요?
How pesky.
얼마나 성가신 일입니까?
ATTORNEY LEE HAN-YOUNG'S OFFICE
이한영 변호사 사무실
ATTORNEY LEE HAN-YOUNG
이한영 변호사
I didn't order that.
나는 그것을 주문하지 않았습니다.
It's on the house.
집에 있어요.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
How much will that be?
그 금액은 얼마나 될까요?
I'll transfer the money.
돈을 이체하겠습니다.
So, it's you.
그래서, 그것은 당신입니다.
You haven't told me the price yet.
아직 가격을 안 알려주셨는데요.
It's you, Attorney Lee Han-young.
바로 당신, 이한영 변호사입니다.
Who the hell are you?
도대체 당신은 누구입니까?
ATTORNEY LEE HAN-YOUNG
이한영 변호사
Oh, no...
아, 아니...
Excuse me.
실례합니다.
Hello?
안녕하세요?
Excuse me?
실례합니다?
ATTORNEY LEE HAN-YOUNG
이한영 변호사
Any information about him?
그에 대한 정보가 있나요?
Hold on.
기다리다.
I found his wallet.
그 사람 지갑을 찾았어요.
Kim Yong-jin, born in 1989.
김용진 1989년생.
You can come out now
이제 나오셔도 됩니다
Mr. Kim.
김 씨.
You know the flash drive I gave you?
내가 준 플래시 드라이브 알지?
I got it from him.
나는 그에게서 그것을 얻었다.
Leave the site immediately.
즉시 사이트를 떠나십시오.
They must've left your fingerprints all over the weapon of murder.
그 사람들이 네 지문을 남긴 게 틀림없어 살인무기 곳곳에.
PROSECUTOR KIM JIN-A SEOUL CENTRAL DISTRICT PROSECUTORS' OFFICE
김진아 검사 서울중앙지방검찰청
This must be Jang Tae-sik getting his revenge.
장태식인가봐 그의 복수를 받고 있습니다.
I'm heading over. Let's meet.
나는 그쪽으로 향하고있다. 만나자.
There's no way you can handle it alone.
혼자 감당할 수 있는 방법은 없습니다.
Are you listening?
듣고 있나요?
Judge Lee.
이 판사.
I'll prove
내가 증명할게
my own innocence.
내 자신의 결백.
I'll call you later.
나중에 전화할게요.
Hello?
안녕하세요?
Damn it.
젠장.
ADMINISTRATIVE LITIGATION
행정소송
Okay, I can do this.
좋아요, 할 수 있어요.
Oh, gosh.
아, 이런.
Over there!
저기요!
That's him.
그 사람이에요.
This way!
이쪽으로!
Hey.
여기요.
Hey!
여기요!
Get him!
그를 잡아!
Over there! That's him!
저기요! 바로 그 사람이에요!
No, it's not me.
아니요, 제가 아닙니다.
- Stay still! - It's not me.
- 가만히 있어! - 내가 아니에요.
I didn't do it.
나는 그것을하지 않았다.
It's not me.
내가 아니야.
I'm innocent.
나는 결백하다.
SEOUL CENTRAL DISTRICT PROSECUTORS' OFFICE
서울중앙지방검찰청
Mr. Lee Han-young.
이한영씨.
You're no longer a judge
당신은 더 이상 판사가 아닙니다
nor an industry senior to me.
나보다 업계 선배도 아니고.
So
그래서
before those pants slip off
그 바지가 미끄러지기 전에
just be nice and work with me here.
그냥 친절하게 대해주시고 여기서 나와 함께 일해주세요.
EVIDENCE
증거
We found your fingerprints on this
여기에서 당신의 지문을 찾았어요
and a trace of the victim's blood.
그리고 피해자의 혈액 흔적.
Do you admit to your murder charge?
살인 혐의를 인정하시나요?
I've been framed.
나는 액자에 걸렸습니다.
How does it seem to you, as a judge?
판사로서 어떻게 보시나요?
If I brought these to the court
내가 이것을 법정에 가져간다면
would Defendant Lee Han-young be guilty or not?
피고인 이한영은? 유죄인가 아닌가?
I didn't kill him.
나는 그를 죽이지 않았습니다.
VICTIM
피해자
I'm not the murderer!
나는 살인자가 아니다!
Stop him!
그만둬!
I've never even met the victim!
피해자를 만난 적도 없어요!
All evidence has been doctored.
모든 증거는 조작되었습니다.
Are you saying you didn't know him at all?
그 사람을 전혀 몰랐다는 겁니까?
Exactly! I don't know him at all.
정확히! 나는 그를 전혀 모른다.
How can you explain all the evidence found, then?
어떻게 설명할 수 있나요? 그럼 모든 증거가 발견됐나요?
A corrupt judge who's been involved
연루된 부패한 판사
in blackmailing, extortion, and taking bribes for cases
협박, 강탈, 사건으로 뇌물을 받는 것
killed an accomplice to destroy evidence
증거인멸을 위해 공범을 살해했다
in this horrifying, unprecedented case.
이 끔찍하고 전례 없는 사건에서요.
According to the police
경찰에 따르면
this judge has been taking bribes of hundreds of millions of won
이 판사는 뇌물을 받았어요 수억 원의
from politicians and corporate leaders
정치인과 기업 지도자로부터
to rule in their favor in court for years.
수년 동안 법정에서 자신에게 유리한 판결을 내렸습니다.
And when investigations began on his accomplice
그리고 조사가 시작되자 그의 공범자에 대해
he made a plan
그는 계획을 세웠어요
to murder him.
그를 살해하기 위해.
Several traces of his attempt to destroy any evidence were found
그의 시도의 여러 흔적 발견된 증거를 없애기 위해
at the site of the murder.
살인 현장에서.
The man was respected in society.
그 남자는 사회에서 존경을 받았습니다.
Still, underneath his judge's robe
그래도 판사 예복 아래에는
he was just a criminal who abused his authority for his benefit.
그 사람은 그냥 범죄자였어 자신의 이익을 위해 자신의 권위를 남용한 사람.
DEFENDANT
DEFENDANT
Defendant Lee Han-young
피고인 이한영
murdered his accomplice
그의 공범을 살해했다
and blackmailed him.
그리고 그를 협박했습니다.
Hence, the prosecution files charges
이에 검찰은 혐의를 적용한다.
against Mr. Lee Han-young.
이한영 씨를 상대로.
Defendant, do you admit to the charges?
피고인, 혐의를 인정합니까?
No.
아니요.
No!
안돼!
Defendant!
피고!
I didn't do it!
나는 그것을하지 않았다!
I didn't do it.
나는 그것을하지 않았다.
I'm...
나는...
I'm innocent.
나는 결백하다.
I'm innocent!
나는 결백하다!
I didn't do it.
나는 그것을하지 않았다.
I'm innocent.
나는 결백하다.
Witness, are you the wife of Accounting Manager Kim Yong-jin
증인, 당신이 아내입니까? 김용진 회계부장
the S Construction employee murdered by Judge Lee Han-young?
S건설 직원 살해 이한영 판사?
Yes.
예.
Has your husband told you anything
남편이 당신에게 말한 것이 있나요?
about Mr. Lee Han-young?
이한영씨에 대해서요?
Yes.
예.
Could you tell me
나에게 말해줄래?
what he said?
그가 뭐라고 했어?
JUDGE
판사
My husband said
남편이 말했어요
Judge Lee was S Construction's legal counsel
이 판사는 S건설 법률고문
who took bribes to rule in favor of people in court.
누가 뇌물을 받았나 법정에서 사람들에게 유리한 판결을 내리기 위해.
Then, my husband got his hands
그러다가 남편이 손을 잡았어요
on the company's funds with Mr. Lee
이씨와 회사 자금에 대해
and said that he feared being caught in an internal audit.
그리고는 두렵다고 말했다 내부감사를 받고 있다.
So
그래서
he went out to see Judge Lee...
그는 이 판사를 만나러 나갔다.
I had no idea when I was sitting up there.
내가 거기 앉아 있을 때는 전혀 몰랐습니다.
I had no idea
나는 전혀 몰랐다
why everyone sitting here
왜 다들 여기 앉아있어?
so desperately said it was unfair.
그래서 필사적으로 불공평하다고 말했다.
This is so unfair.
이건 너무 불공평해요.
So unfair.
너무 불공평해요.
My husband took bribes
남편이 뇌물을 받았어요
to play in favor of people in court.
법정에서 사람들의 편을 들기 위해.
He wanted to open an attorney's office
그는 변호사 사무실을 열고 싶었습니다
for money laundering reasons, too.
돈세탁의 이유도 마찬가지다.
I tried to stop him
나는 그를 막으려고 노력했다
and he said he wanted a divorce.
그리고 그는 이혼하고 싶다고 말했습니다.
Article 152, Paragraph 1 of the Criminal Act.
제152조 제1항 형법의.
"A witness who, having sworn according to Acts"
"증인이요. 사도행전에 따라 맹세하였으니"
"gives false statement, shall be punished"
"허위 진술, 처벌받을 것"
"by imprisonment for less than five years or by a fine under ten million won."
"5년 이하의 징역 아니면 천만 원 이하의 벌금에 처해집니다."
- Defendant. - Paragraph Two.
- 피고인. - 단락 2.
"As regards a criminal or disciplinary case"
"범죄자에 관해서는 아니면 징계 사건"
"a witness who, for the purpose of causing injury to an accused"
"증인은 그 목적을 위해 피고인에게 상해를 입혔다"
"commits the crime of the preceding paragraph"
"범죄를 저질렀다. 앞 단락의 "
"shall be punished by imprisonment for less than ten years."
"징역에 처해질 것이다 10년도 채 안 됐어요."
Defendant, what do you think you're doing?
피고인, 당신은 무엇을 하고 있다고 생각합니까?
I'm just stating the violations
나는 단지 위반 사항을 언급하고 있을 뿐입니다.
Ms. Yu Se-hee is making
유세희씨가 만들고 있는
right now.
지금 당장.
What is he talking about?
그가 무슨 말을 하는 걸까요?
You're kidding me.
농담하는 거군요.
What happened to you?
당신에게 무슨 일이 일어났나요?
You know your father was kicked out
너희 아버지가 쫓겨난 거 알지?
of his care home, right?
그 사람 요양원에서요, 그렇죠?
You didn't know?
몰랐어요?
Here.
여기.
What did they do with my dad?
그 사람들이 우리 아빠한테 무슨 짓을 한 걸까요?
There's one more.
하나 더 있습니다.
Have you no conscience?
양심이 없나요?
You should've seen it coming. You betrayed them first.
당신은 그것이 오는 것을 봤어야 했어요. 당신이 먼저 그들을 배신했습니다.
What the hell did you do with my dad?
도대체 아빠한테 무슨 짓을 한 거야?
You're such a terrible son.
넌 정말 끔찍한 아들이야.
Seriously.
진지하게.
But the worst thing would be
하지만 최악의 상황은
for you to die before your father.
네가 네 아버지보다 먼저 죽게 하려 함이라.
What did you do with my dad...
아빠한테 무슨 짓을 한 거야...
What do you mean?
무슨 뜻인가요?
Some guys will be waiting for you
어떤 남자들이 당신을 기다리고 있을 거예요
at the detention center.
구치소에서.
Don't let them torture you.
그들이 당신을 고문하도록 놔두지 마세요.
Take this as soon as you get there.
거기 도착하자마자 이것을 가져가세요.
Whatever kills you, it'll be recorded as an accident.
당신을 죽이는 것이 무엇이든, 사고로 기록되겠죠.
Is this how you killed Choi Jong-hak, too?
최종학도 이렇게 죽였나요?
I guess this isn't so bad for you yet.
내 생각에 이것은 아직 당신에게 그다지 나쁘지 않은 것 같습니다.
You still have time to care about others?
아직 다른 사람을 배려할 시간이 있나요?
Is Chairman Jang behind it?
배후에는 장회장이 있는가?
You're so curious. Of course, you're a judge.
당신은 너무 궁금합니다. 물론, 당신은 판사입니다.
But you weren't like this in trials.
하지만 시련 속에서는 그렇지 않았습니다.
Think about it carefully.
신중하게 생각해보세요.
Starting from your wife
아내부터 시작해서
it's odd that you have absolutely nobody, isn't it?
당신이 가지고 있다는 게 이상해요 전혀 아무도 없지 않습니까?
Chairman Jang wasn't the only one in on this.
장 회장만이 아니었다. 이것에 대해.
From the arrest to the prosecution and the trial
체포 이후 검찰과 재판에
don't you think things have progressed too quickly?
상황이 진전된 것 같지 않아? 너무 빨리?
Chief Justice Kang is very interested in the upcoming trial.
강 대법원장은 다가오는 재판에 매우 관심이 있습니다.
Chief Justice Kang Sin-jin.
강신진 대법원장.
At least you won't die in confusion, knowing who's behind it.
적어도 당신은 혼란 속에 죽지는 않을 것입니다. 배후에 누가 있는지 아는 것.
And let me tell you this in case you're curious.
그리고 이걸 말해줄게 혹시 궁금하신가요?
You know the money you hid
당신이 숨긴 돈을 당신은 알고 있습니다
in the safe in the closet of the care home? I took that all.
옷장 안 금고에 요양원에서요? 내가 그걸 다 가져갔어.
You saved quite a bit for a puppet.
꼭두각시를 위해 꽤 많은 비용을 절약했습니다.
What? What's wrong?
무엇? 무슨 일이야?
You can't even use that money after you die.
그 돈도 못쓰잖아 당신이 죽은 후에.
What?
무엇?
You piece of shit!
이 똥같은 놈아!
This is what happens when a shithead tries to be a judge!
이런 일이 일어난다 멍청이가 판사가 되려고 할 때!
You should've just lived your life as a piece of shit.
넌 그냥 네 인생을 살았어야 했어 똥처럼.
Who knows? Maybe you could've been recycled.
누가 알겠어요? 어쩌면 재활용되었을 수도 있습니다.
You dumbass.
멍청아.
Take it as soon as you get there, alright?
거기 도착하자마자 가져가세요, 알았죠?
Thanks for your hard work.
당신의 노고에 감사드립니다.
He's such a jerk, you know?
그 사람 정말 바보야, 알지?
Emergency!
비상!
Call an ambulance!
구급차를 불러주세요!
Ambulance!
구급차!
I told you to take it at the detention center.
내가 가져가라고 했어 구치소에서.
Idiot.
바보.
His heartbeat and breathing are very unstable.
그의 심장박동과 호흡은 매우 불안정합니다.
- Please prepare gastric lavage. - Yes, sir.
- 위세척물을 준비해주세요. - 네, 선생님.
He's reacting to a drug.
그는 약물에 반응하고 있습니다.
- Where's the closest hospital? - Within 15 minutes away.
- 가장 가까운 병원이 어디예요? - 15분 이내 거리입니다.
Check on the patient in 30 minutes
30분 안에 환자 상태 확인
- and let me know. - Yes, sir.
- 그리고 알려주세요. - 네, 선생님.
Help!
돕다!
Have you checked upstairs?
위층에서 확인해 보셨나요?
Contact the prison guard.
교도관에게 연락하세요.
Sorry.
죄송합니다.
I told you to keep an eye on him!
내가 그 사람을 잘 지켜보라고 했잖아!
I can't die a piece of shit.
난 똥 하나도 죽을 수 없습니다.
Yes, Kim Yoon-hyeok speaking.
네, 김윤혁입니다.
Go on.
계속하세요.
CLOTHING DONATION BIN
의류 기부 상자
- Who's that man? - What is he doing?
- 저 사람은 누구죠? - 그 사람 뭐하는 거예요?
The Seoul Metropolitan Council has passed
서울시의회가 통과됐다.
the 18th ordinance of 2025
the 18th ordinance of 2025
to expel all the homeless on the streets
거리의 노숙자들을 모두 추방하기 위해
for improved city aesthetics and public safety.
향상된 도시 미학을 위해 공공 안전.
This has left the homeless
이로 인해 노숙자가 생겼습니다.
to hide in underpasses
지하도에 숨다
abandoned buildings, and sewers.
버려진 건물과 하수구.
Die!
주사위!
Die! What do you want?
주사위! 당신은 무엇을 원하세요?
Dad.
아빠.
Dad!
아빠!
Please
제발
save me.
나를 구해주세요.
This is where it ends.
이것이 끝나는 곳입니다.
It's so unfair to die like this.
이렇게 죽는 건 정말 불공평해요.
When I've only begun
내가 이제 막 시작했을 때
to want to live as the real Lee Han-young now.
살고 싶다 이제 진짜 이한영처럼.
Mother.
어머니.
I'm sorry, Mother.
죄송해요, 어머니.
Sorry.
죄송합니다.
I'm so sorry.
정말 죄송해요.
Give me a chance.
나에게 기회를 주세요.
Please give me a chance...
저에게 기회를 주세요...
Mother, I'm sorry.
어머니, 미안해요.
I'm so sorry.
정말 죄송해요.
Please. I'm sorry.
제발. 죄송합니다.
Defendant Lee Han-young.
피고인 이한영.
Does this still feel unfair to you?
아직도 이것이 불공평하다고 생각하시나요?
Do you still believe you're innocent?
아직도 당신이 결백하다고 믿나요?
I'm a cowardly son.
나는 겁쟁이 아들이다.
I'm a murderer.
나는 살인자입니다.
I'm
나는
an accomplice with the devil.
악마의 공범자.
guilty.
유죄.
Defendant Lee Han-young is
피고인 이한영은
SHIN NAM-SUK
신남석
THE VICTIMS OF GOJIN CHEMICAL
고진화학의 피해자들
PRESIDING JUDGE LEE HAN-YOUNG
재판장 이한영
On April 20, 2025, around 1:30 a.m.
2025년 4월 20일 오전 1시 30분쯤.
the Defendant attempted to break into a home
피고인이 시도한 집에 침입하다
on Jeongeui-ro, Cheonan, Chungcheongnam-do
충청남도 천안시 정의로에
through a window
창문을 통해
with the intention to steal money and goods.
훔치려는 의도로 돈과 물건.
However, the victim's boyfriend found him
그런데 피해자의 남자친구가 그를 발견했습니다.
leaving it as a theft attempt.
절도 시도로 남겨 두세요.
Your Honor, are you okay?
재판장님, 괜찮으세요?
Your Honor.
재판장님.
Your Honor!
재판장님!
Huh?
뭐?
Oh!
오!
- Oh! - Huh?
- 오! - 뭐?
He was the prosecutor for my first case.
그는 나의 첫 번째 사건의 검사였습니다.
That is all.
그게 전부입니다.
I heard about life flashing before our eyes when dying.
인생이 번쩍인다는 얘기를 들었어 죽을 때 우리 눈앞에서.
I guess my flashback isn't over?
내 회상은 아직 끝나지 않은 것 같은데?
Your Honor.
재판장님.
Defendant Kim Sang-jin committed the crime
피고인 김상진이 범행을 저질렀다.
out of impulse, in starvation.
충동적으로, 배고픈 상태에서.
Kim Sang-jin?
김상진?
He admits to all his charges
그는 자신의 혐의를 모두 인정한다
and deeply regrets his actions.
그리고 그의 행동을 깊이 후회합니다.
Kim Sang-jin.
김상진.
Kim Sang-jin!
김상진!
What?
무엇?
Kim Sang-jin, you son of a bitch.
김상진, 이 개자식아.
Your Honor.
재판장님.
Your Honor, please calm down!
재판장님, 진정하십시오!
I still wake up from time to time at the thought of you.
나는 아직도 가끔씩 일어난다. 당신 생각에.
Why? It was just an attempted theft!
왜? 그것은 단지 절도 시도였을 뿐입니다!
Theft, my ass! You know nothing.
도둑놈아, 망할 놈아! 당신은 아무것도 모른다.
Okay, hold on.
좋아요, 잠깐만요.
Why do I sound like this?
왜 이런 소리가 나는 걸까요?
Sure, this is my chance to get all my anger out before I go, right?
물론이죠. 이번이 기회입니다. 가기 전에 화를 다 내는 거죠, 그렇죠?
Okay.
좋아요.
It's okay. I'm fine.
괜찮아요. 잘 지내요.
Hey, don't play dumb. Look straight into my eyes.
이봐, 바보같은 짓은 하지 마 내 눈을 똑바로 봐.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
Do you know what you've done? Yeah.
당신이 무슨 짓을 했는지 아세요? 응.
You know what you did.
당신은 당신이 무엇을했는지 알고 있습니다.
Defendant Kim Sang-jin!
피고인 김상진!
I sentence you to the death penalty!
나는 당신에게 사형을 선고합니다!
You know how much I wanted to do that?
내가 얼마나 그러고 싶었는지 알아?
You have no idea!
당신은 전혀 모른다!
I'm ready!
난 준비됐어!
Let's go!
갑시다!
Wherever it is, heaven or hell, I'm ready!
천국이든 지옥이든 나는 준비가 되어있습니다!
Alright!
괜찮은!
Yes!
예!
Am I in hell?
내가 지옥에 있는 걸까?
Sure, then.
그럼요.
Alright, let's go!
좋아, 가자!
Just go already.
그냥 가세요.
CHUNGNAM DISTRICT COURT
충남지방법원
Don't tell me I'm in hell.
내가 지옥에 있다고 말하지 마세요.
Man.
남성.
I didn't think I'd need to use the bathroom after death.
나는 생각하지 않았다 나는 죽은 후에 화장실을 사용해야 할 것입니다.
Is this some post-mortem service?
이게 사후 서비스인가요?
Wow!
우와!
I had these glasses ten years ago.
나는 이 안경을 10년 전에 가지고 있었습니다.
Watch your feet.
발 조심하세요.
Stop getting in my way!
방해하지 마세요!
MAY 7, 2025
2025년 5월 7일
2025?
2025년?
Wow!
우와!
Get your head away.
머리를 치워라.
No way.
안 돼요.
Damn it!
젠장!
"Damn it"?
"젠장"?
If this is 2025
지금이 2025년이라면
is this Lim Jeong-sik, the Senior Presiding Judge?
임정식인가요? 수석 재판관?
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
Are you back in your right mind now?
이제 정신이 돌아왔나요?
Judge Lee
이 판사
I know that was your first sole trial
그게 너의 첫 번째 단독 재판이었다는 걸 알아
but you went too far!
하지만 넌 너무 멀리 갔어!
How can you sentence an attempted theft to death?
어떻게 문장을 만들 수 있나요? 절도 시도?
You think Kim Sang-jin is a serial killer?
김상진이 연쇄살인범이라고 생각하시나요?
How did you know?
어떻게 알았나요?
You're still crazy.
당신은 아직도 미쳤어요.
Wake up!
깨우다!
You were fine as an accompanying judge.
동행심사위원으로서는 괜찮았습니다.
I'll take care of this. You'll be on probation.
이건 제가 처리하겠습니다. 당신은 보호 관찰을 받게 될 것입니다.
- No, that's not it. - Say that one more time!
- 아뇨, ​​그게 아닙니다. - 한 번 더 말해보세요!
Or I'll make your first sole trial your last.
아니면 내가 만들게요 첫 번째 단독 재판이 마지막입니다.
Maybe this is for real.
어쩌면 이것이 진짜일 수도 있다.
Sir
선생님
is it 2025 this year?
올해는 2025년인가요?
I'm taking a dump!
나는 쓰레기를 버릴거야!
Just leave already!
그냥 떠나세요!
Why are you still talking?
왜 아직도 얘기하고 있어요?
CHUNGNAM DISTRICT PROSECUTORS' OFFICE
충남지방검찰청
CASE NUMBER: 2025H141121 COURT: CHUNGNAM DISTRICT COURT
사건번호: 2025H141121 법원 : 충남지방법원
Stop it!
그만해!
Can you just leave already?
벌써 떠날 수 있나요?
Oh?
오?
Kim Yoon-hyeok?
김윤혁?
Look at that.
저것 좀 보세요.
What the hell did you do with my dad?
도대체 아빠한테 무슨 짓을 한 거야?
Take this as soon as you get there.
거기 도착하자마자 이것을 가져가세요.
Whatever kills you, it'll be recorded as an accident.
당신을 죽이는 것이 무엇이든, 사고로 기록되겠죠.
You piece of shit!
이 똥같은 놈아!
This is what happens when a shithead tries to be a judge!
이런 일이 일어난다 멍청이가 판사가 되려고 할 때!
Huh?
뭐?
You son of a bitch!
이 개자식아!
Why?
왜?
This is before anything happened!
이건 무슨 일이 일어나기 전이에요!
Oh, what?
아, 뭐?
You okay, Lee?
괜찮아, 리?
What's wrong? Are you okay?
무슨 일이야? 괜찮으세요?
I'm so thankful to have you when nobody is here to help me!
당신이 있어서 정말 고마워요 나를 도와줄 사람이 아무도 없을 때!
Hey.
여기요.
What's with you?
당신은 무엇입니까?
Did Mr. Lim scold you big time?
임 선생님이 크게 혼내셨나요?
In the bathroom.
화장실에서.
Forgive him. You went too far.
그를 용서하세요. 당신은 너무 멀리 갔다.
Yeah, and what you did was
응, 그리고 네가 한 일은
way beyond going too far.
너무 멀리 가는 것 이상으로.
Okay!
좋아요!
Alright.
괜찮은.
Let's see.
어디 보자.
What do I do?
어떻게 해야 하나요?
What do I do now?
이제 어떻게 해야 하나요?
Oh, yes, Mother.
아, 그래요, 어머니.
What brings the busy man to call, Your Honor?
바쁜 사람이 전화를 하는 이유는 무엇입니까? 재판장님?
Are you out of food to eat?
먹을 음식이 없나요?
No
아니요
I just wanted to hear your voice, Mother.
저는 단지 당신의 목소리를 듣고 싶었을 뿐입니다, 어머니.
Huh? "Mother"?
뭐? "어머니"?
Mother
어머니
you're healthy, right?
당신은 건강해요, 그렇죠?
Are you taking your asthma meds?
천식약을 복용하고 있나요?
And your inhaler.
그리고 흡입기.
You always have it on you, right?
당신은 항상 그것을 가지고 있습니다. 그렇죠?
Who are you?
누구세요?
This is a scam, isn't it?
이건 사기죠, 그렇죠?
- Listen, my son is a judge. - Mother, it's me.
- 내 아들이 판사예요. - 어머니, 저예요.
How dare you try to scam a judge's mother?
어떻게 감히 판사의 어머니를 속이려고 합니까?
You sound like a young man.
당신은 젊은 사람처럼 들립니다.
If you have time for scams
사기를 칠 시간이 있다면
call and check on your mom instead.
대신 엄마에게 전화해서 확인해 보세요.
No, Mother, it's me.
아니요, 어머니, 저예요.
I don't know who you are, alright?
당신이 누구인지 모르겠어요, 그렇죠?
My son has never called me "Mother" in his life.
내 아들은 나를 '엄마'라고 불러본 적이 없다. 그의 인생에서.
Mother! Mom!
어머니! 엄마!
Mom!
엄마!
- Mom... - Crazy guy.
- Mom... - 미친놈.
What was that about asthma?
천식에 관한 내용은 무엇이었나요?
My Han-young
마이한영
has never called me "Mother" in his life.
그는 평생 동안 나를 "어머니"라고 부르지 않았습니다.
But wait.
하지만 기다려라.
He sounded just like him.
그 사람도 꼭 그 사람처럼 들렸어요.
Huh?
뭐?
Oh!
오!
Oh, right!
아, 그렇죠!
This is before I started calling her "Mother."
이건 내가 그녀에게 전화를 걸기 전이야 "어머니."
MS. SHIN
MS. 신
Right, this was before she got asthma.
맞아요, 천식이 생기기 전이었어요.
Hello there, Ms. Shin!
안녕하세요, 신 선생님!
That's my son, for sure.
물론 저 사람은 내 아들이다.
- Were you the one who called just now? - No.
- 방금 전화한 사람이 당신인가요? - 아니요.
Did something happen?
무슨 일이 있었나요?
S GROUP
S그룹
COMPANY PROFILE
회사 프로필
S Group...
S그룹...
JANG TAE-SIK
장태식
Ten years?
10년?
- Please. - Let go!
- 제발. - 놔!
Jang Tae-sik is still just the owner of S Shopping now
장태식은 아직은 S쇼핑의 오너일 뿐
and the Chairman of S Group is his father, Jang Yong-hyeon.
S그룹 회장은 그의 아버지 장용현.
S Shopping had a lot of issues from tax evasion
S쇼핑은 문제가 많았어요 탈세로 인해
to embezzlement and slush funds
to embezzlement and slush funds
but wiggled out every time.
하지만 매번 흔들렸다.
KOREAN COURT KNOWLEDGE SUPPORT SYSTEM
한국 법원 지식 지원 시스템
KANG SIN-JIN
강신진
SEARCH RESULT
검색결과
Kang Sin-jin hasn't become
강신진은 안됐어
the Chief Justice yet, either.
아직 대법원장도 아니고.
Wow.
우와.
Unbelievable.
믿을 수 없는.
How is this even possible?
이것이 어떻게 가능합니까?
I've come exactly ten years back in time.
나는 정확히 10년 전으로 돌아왔습니다.
Please
제발
save me.
나를 구해주세요.
It's so unfair to die like this.
이렇게 죽는 건 정말 불공평해요.
When I've only begun
내가 이제 막 시작했을 때
to want to live as the real Lee Han-young now.
살고 싶다 이제 진짜 이한영처럼.
Defendant Lee Han-young is
피고인 이한영은
guilty.
유죄.
That's right.
좋아요.
I'm a sinner who wasted his life by making wrong choices.
나는 인생을 낭비한 죄인이다 잘못된 선택을 해서.
This means this life is a probation period
이번 생은 수습기간이란 뜻이야
for Defendant Lee Han-young.
피고인 이한영에 대하여.
That means
즉
I should straighten things out, starting with Kim Sang-jin's case.
상황을 바로잡아야 하는데, 김상진 사건부터 시작된다.
Gosh, my outfit.
이런, 내 옷.
Haven't worn these in forever.
영원히 이것을 착용하지 않았습니다.
Wait, which car was mine?
잠깐만요, 어느 차가 내 차였나요?
My car back then was...
그 당시 내 차는...
non-existent.
존재하지 않습니다.
STONE JEONG-HO
스톤정호
When I became Haenal's puppet
내가 해날의 꼭두각시가 되었을 때
I even ditched my best friend, Seok Jeong-ho.
가장 친한 친구마저도 버렸어요 석정호.
But if this is 2025, I can still...
하지만 지금이 2025년이라면 아직은...
- Jeong-ho. - Hey!
- 정호. - 여기요!
What brings my crazy judge to call?
미친 판사가 왜 전화를 하게 된 걸까요?
You became a star after moving to Chungcheongnam-do.
당신은 스타가 되었습니다 충청남도로 이사한 후.
You know, you've gone viral as "the crazy judge."
아시다시피, 당신은 입소문이 났어요 "미친 판사"로.
Did you call me to show off?
자랑하려고 나한테 전화한 거야?
DEATH PENALTY FOR THE FAILED THIEF
실패한 도둑에 대한 사형
What do you mean?
무슨 뜻이에요?
You sentenced a thief to the death penalty
당신은 도둑에게 사형을 선고했습니다
when he hadn't even eaten in three days.
사흘 동안 아무것도 먹지 않았을 때.
No wonder they call you "the crazy judge."
사람들이 당신을 "미친 판사"라고 부르는 것도 당연합니다.
Kids don't want to become judges because of you.
아이들은 판사가 되고 싶어하지 않는다 당신 때문에.
Hey!
여기요!
You just don't know who he really is.
당신은 그 사람이 실제로 누구인지 모릅니다.
What don't I know?
내가 뭘 몰라?
He's just a petty, failed thief.
그는 단지 하찮고 실패한 도둑일 뿐입니다.
Forget it.
잊어버리세요.
Let me ask you a favor.
부탁 좀 할게요.
I need to get a used car.
중고차를 구해야 해요.
Do you know anyone?
아는 사람 있나요?
You didn't sound drunk when we called yesterday.
취한 것 같지 않았어 어제 우리가 전화했을 때.
- What? - Remember?
- 무엇? - 기억하다?
You already called me about a used car yesterday.
이미 나한테 전화했잖아 어제 중고차에 대해서요.
Don't you remember?
기억하지 못하시나요?
Oh, yeah, of course, I remember it.
아, 네, 물론 기억해요.
I'm just asking again.
나는 단지 다시 묻는다.
- When will the car be ready? - Tomorrow.
- 차는 언제 준비되나요? - 내일.
Tomorrow? Tomorrow...
내일? 내일...
Okay, sure.
알았어, 물론이지.
Thanks.
감사해요.
Hey, Han-young...
안녕 한영아...
Maybe being a judge is tiring.
어쩌면 판사가 되는 것이 피곤할 수도 있습니다.
Don't mess with the mayor, alright?
시장님한테 장난치지 마세요, 알았죠?
- Clean them up. - Okay.
- 청소하세요. - 좋아요.
Damn it.
젠장.
Nobody had known it by this point
이때까지는 아무도 그것을 알지 못했다
but Kim Sang-jin was a serial killer who'd killed three people already.
하지만 김상진은 연쇄살인마였다 벌써 세 사람을 죽인 사람.
But I fell for his tears
하지만 나는 그의 눈물에 반했어요
and sentenced him to probation.
그리고 그에게 집행유예를 선고했다.
I started getting nightmares
악몽을 꾸기 시작했어요
because the guy I put on probation killed
내가 집행유예를 선고한 사람이 죽었으니까
yet another victim.
또 다른 피해자.
Sir...
선생님...
Huh?
응?
Judge Lee!
이 판사님!
Prosecutor Park Cheol-woo? What are you doing here?
박철우 검사? 여기서 뭐하는거야?
I'm here for a field inspection.
현장 점검을 위해 왔습니다.
Don't you read case files?
사건 파일을 읽지 않나요?
The site is the house near the terminal, not here.
현장은 터미널 근처 주택이며, 여기는 아니야.
Why are you here?
당신은 왜 여기에 있습니까?
Well, no wonder.
글쎄요.
How can you get in here?
여기에 어떻게 들어갈 수 있나요?
Why would you go in?
왜 들어가겠어요?
Why are you here, then?
그렇다면 당신은 왜 여기에 있습니까?
Because you...
왜냐면 당신은...
- You said you knew nothing! - You scared me.
- 아무것도 모른다고 했잖아! - 당신은 나를 겁줬어요.
You should be near the terminal, at the crime scene.
터미널 근처에 있어야 하고, 범죄 현장에서.
Why are you here?
당신은 왜 여기에 있습니까?
I asked you first.
제가 먼저 물어봤습니다.
Why don't you answer first, too, then?
그럼 당신도 먼저 대답해 보는 게 어때?
You already broke the Internet as "the crazy judge."
당신은 이미 인터넷을 끊었습니다 "미친 판사"로.
I guess I'll add "rude" to that.
거기에 "무례하다"라는 말을 추가할 것 같아요.
We don't know if I'm the rude one yet.
내가 무례한 사람인지는 아직 모르겠습니다.
Aren't you also here because something is fishy?
너도 여기 있지 않니? 뭔가 수상해서?
What's fishy?
수상한 게 뭐야?
He climbed a wall out of hunger.
그는 배고픔 때문에 벽을 기어올랐다.
I came to check just in case
혹시 모르니 확인하러 왔어요
but I doubt we'll find anything here.
하지만 여기서 아무것도 찾을 수 없을 것 같아요.
What would we...
우리는 무엇을...
possibly find around here?
혹시 이 근처에서 찾을 수 있나요?
Huh?
뭐?
Oh?
오?
- What are you, a princess? - My gosh.
- 당신은 공주입니까? - 맙소사.
Let me do it.
내가 해보자.
Just like this.
그냥 이렇습니다.
- Easy. All good. - Wow.
- 쉬운. 모두 좋습니다. - 우와.
See? Easy.
보다? 쉬운.
Isn't this property damage?
이거 재산 피해 아닌가요?
I wouldn't call it "damage." Nothing's broken.
나는 그것을 "손상"이라고 부르지 않을 것입니다. 아무것도 깨지지 않았습니다.
Without a warrant?
영장 없이요?
Anyway, since you took it off, get the door for me.
어쨌든, 네가 그걸 벗은 이후로, 나한테 문 좀 열어줘.
I shouldn't have colluded with him.
나는 그 사람과 공모하지 말았어야 했어요.
This is crazy.
이건 미친 짓이야.
What are you possibly trying to find?
당신은 무엇을 찾으려고 노력하고 있습니까?
You've dealt with violent crimes, right?
당신은 강력범죄를 다뤘죠, 그렇죠?
Of course.
물론.
I'm opening it.
나는 그것을 열고있다.
One
하나
two
둘
three!
삼!
Goodness!
선량!
Corpses.
시체.
What are corpses doing here?
여기서 시체는 무엇을 하고 있는 걸까요?
Let go! My goodness.
가자! 이럴 수가.
Corpses...
시체...
There's something inside! What is it?
안에 뭔가 있어요! 그것은 무엇입니까?
It's almost open.
거의 열려있습니다.
- Oh? Hold on. - Why?
- 오? 기다리다. - 왜?
What?
무엇?
Huh?
뭐?
Do you just like to scream
그냥 비명 지르는 걸 좋아하시나요?
- every time you open a fridge? - It's not here.
- 냉장고를 열 때마다? - 여기 없어요.
It should be here.
여기에 있어야합니다.
What are you even looking for?
당신은 무엇을 찾고 있습니까?
Stop asking me questions and start looking!
나한테 질문 좀 그만해 그리고 찾기 시작하세요!
Whatever!
무엇이든!
I thought these were bones!
I thought these were bones!
You're not explaining anything!
당신은 아무것도 설명하지 않습니다!
I must find proof that Kim Sang-jin is a serial killer.
증거를 찾아야 해요 김상진이 연쇄살인범이라는 것.
His third murder happened
세 번째 살인이 일어났다
three days before getting arrested for attempted theft.
체포되기 사흘 전 도난 시도에 대해.
And it was recorded
그리고 녹음됐어요
that the victim was found in the fridge.
피해자가 냉장고에서 발견됐다는 것.
That's enough. Come back out now.
그것으로 충분합니다. 지금 다시 나오세요.
Before we get caught for breaking in and property damage.
우리가 잡히기 전에 침입 및 재산 피해에 대비하세요.
Come out.
나오세요.
BLEACH
표백제
Could he have had a temporary place for keeping his corpses?
임시로 자리를 잡을 수 있었을까 시체를 보관했기 때문에?
BLEACH
표백제
PURE BLEACH
퓨어 블리치
That's a different brand.
그건 다른 브랜드입니다.
Why are people in this area so serious about house cleaning?
이 동네 사람들은 왜 이렇게 심각해? 집 청소에 대해서?
Is that death sentence-worthy, too?
그것도 사형 선고를 받을 만한가요?
I didn't know you were the type to hold grudges.
나는 몰랐다 당신은 원한을 품는 타입이었어요.
Do you even know me?
당신도 나를 아시나요?
No, I just get a vibe.
아니, 그냥 느낌이 와요.
What's with those hands behind his back like an old man?
등뒤에 있는 저 손은 뭐야? 늙은이처럼?
That's a good counterstrike.
좋은 반격이군요.
Good choice! Good eye.
좋은 선택! 좋은 눈.
This is what I find disappointing.
이것이 내가 실망스럽다고 생각하는 점이다.
What if he'd taken some swings before this?
그 사람이 스윙을 좀 했다면 어땠을까? 이 전에?
You an Eagles fan?
이글스 팬이신가요?
How did you know?
어떻게 알았나요?
I'm here because you said you'd pay, but I'm leaving right away.
당신이 돈을 내겠다고 해서 내가 여기 왔어요. 하지만 난 바로 떠날 거야.
I don't want to have anything to do with you...
나는 아무것도 갖고 싶지 않다 너랑 할게...
Hey!
이봐!
Oh, my gosh!
오, 맙소사!
That was...
그건 ...
Another out at first base!
1루에 또 아웃!
It's okay. The Eagles will win, anyway.
괜찮아요. 어쨌든 이글스는 승리할 것이다.
But it'll go overtime.
하지만 시간이 초과될 거예요.
A walk-off home run in the bottom of the 11th.
끝내기 홈런 11일 하단에.
The Eagles wins.
이글스가 승리합니다.
Are you spreading false information?
허위정보를 퍼뜨리고 계시나요?
You want to bet?
내기를 원하시나요?
The loser has to grant the winner's wish, no matter what.
패자는 승자의 소원을 들어줘야 하고, 무슨 일이 있어도.
You down?
당신은 다운?
Down?
아래에?
- Down. - Water.
- 아래에. - 물.
DISABLED THE DOOR LOCK SOUND
도어 잠금 소리를 비활성화했습니다.
THE ALIBI AND THE FACTS MATCH
알리바이와 사실이 일치함
All of this is about theft.
이 모든 것은 도난에 관한 것입니다.
No.
아니요.
The third victim's body was definitely found
세 번째 피해자의 시신은 확실히 찾았어
in the fridge.
냉장고에.
Was the case record wrong?
사건기록이 잘못됐나요?
No.
아니요.
From what I remember, there were even photos from the site.
제가 기억하는 바에 따르면, 사이트의 사진도있었습니다.
Unbelievable.
믿을 수 없는.
It's like he's lost his mind.
마치 정신을 잃은 것 같습니다.
Good morning.
좋은 아침이에요.
Hey.
여기요.
Was he here all night?
그 사람 밤새 여기에 있었나요?
It seems like it.
그런 것 같습니다.
Why did he sentence him to the death penalty?
그 사람은 왜 형을 선고받았나 사형까지?
I'm not really sure, either.
나도 잘 모르겠어.
Weren't you classmates?
동창 아니었어?
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
Tell him to come to my office after breakfast.
그 사람에게 내 사무실로 오라고 전해줘 아침 식사 후.
Come on. It's too early for this.
어서 해봐요. 그러기엔 너무 이르다.
My stomach has been so upset lately.
요즘 배가 너무 안 좋아졌어요.
Tell him to come to my office.
그에게 내 사무실로 오라고 전해주세요.
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
- Have a good day. - Okay.
- 좋은 하루 보내세요. - 좋아요.
It's too early for something so gross.
너무 심한 일을 하기에는 너무 이르다.
Why does he keep coming here? It's so awkward.
그 사람은 왜 계속 여기로 오는 걸까요? 너무 어색해요.
It's the good Kim Yoon-hyeok.
좋은 김윤혁이다.
I know I'm a good person.
나는 내가 좋은 사람이라는 것을 압니다.
Did you sleep here?
여기서 잤어요?
Yeah.
응.
Mr. Lim wants to see you in his office.
임씨가 사무실에서 당신을 만나고 싶어합니다.
Okay.
좋아요.
It hasn't changed a bit.
조금도 변하지 않았습니다.
It's all the same.
모두 똑같습니다.
Look at the phone.
전화기를 보세요.
CHUNGNAM DISTRICT COURT
충남지방법원
Are you kidding?
농담하는 건가요?
Did you call me, sir?
나한테 전화했어요 선생님?
I'll close the door for you.
내가 문을 닫아드릴게요.
- Have a seat. - Yes, sir.
- 자리에 앉으세요. - 네, 선생님.
Gosh, you startled me.
맙소사, 당신 때문에 놀랐어요.
Acting like a presiding judge means nothing.
재판장처럼 행동 아무것도 의미하지 않습니다.
Keep causing trouble from the start
처음부터 계속 문제를 일으키고
and you'll spend your whole career moving around regional courts.
and you'll spend your whole career 지방 법원을 돌아 다닙니다.
I know Chief Judge Baek Yi-seok
나는 백이석 부장판사를 안다.
got on the wrong side of the higher-ups and came here
윗사람과 반대되는 입장에 빠졌어 그리고 여기까지 왔어
but you need to move up to Seoul.
하지만 서울로 올라가야 해요.
What's your plan for Kim?
김 씨의 계획은 무엇인가요?
It was a theft attempt out of hunger.
배고픔에 따른 절도 시도였습니다.
I'll make an appropriate verdict as per the standards.
적절한 판결을 내리겠습니다 표준에 따라.
You're not crazy now?
이제 미친 거 아니지?
Please continue
계속해주세요
to supervise me with a critical eye.
비판적인 눈으로 나를 감독하기 위해.
Taking over the Internet as a judge is an experience, too.
판사로서 인터넷을 장악하는 것은 경험도요.
Let me know anytime if you want attention.
관심을 원하시면 언제든지 말씀해주세요.
I'll give you some.
내가 좀 줄게.
Yes, sir!
네, 선생님!
You may leave.
떠날 수도 있습니다.
Why do I still feel like something is off?
왜 아직도 뭔가 문제가 있는 것 같은 느낌이 들까요?
The verdict is ready.
판결이 준비되었습니다.
I sentence Defendant Kim Sang-jin
피고인 김상진에게 형을 선고한다
to one year in prison.
징역 1년.
However
그러나
the court grants probation of two years
법원은 2년의 집행유예를 선고한다
starting from the date of the final judgment.
날짜부터 시작해서 최후의 심판의 내용입니다.
DEFENDANT
피고인
Where have I seen him?
내가 그 사람을 어디서 본 걸까?
- He's coming. - Judge Lee!
- 그 사람이 오고 있어요. - 이 판사님!
Judge Lee.
이 판사.
It was the death penalty last time.
지난번에는 사형이었습니다.
Isn't a year in prison and two on probation
징역 1년 아닌가요 그리고 두 명은 집행유예 중
too dramatic?
너무 드라마틱한데?
My verdict last time was more dramatic.
지난번 내 평결은 더 극적이었습니다.
I sincerely apologize as a judge
판사로서 진심으로 사과드립니다
who should make fair, logical judgment.
공정하고 논리적인 판단을 내려야 하는 사람.
- Oh, I... - Let's wrap it up here.
- 아, 난... - 여기서 마무리하겠습니다.
Has everyone eaten?
다들 식사하셨나요?
Eat something and get some rest.
뭐라도 먹고 좀 쉬세요.
Excuse me, then.
그럼 실례합니다.
Look at that charisma.
저 카리스마 좀 보세요.
Was that a presiding judge just now?
방금 그 사람이 재판장이었나요?
Wasn't that his first sole trial?
그게 그의 첫 번째 단독 재판이 아니었나요?
Hey, did we get a photo of him?
야, 우리 그 사람 사진 봤어?
- Hold on. - Darn it!
- 기다리다. - 젠장!
Let's go.
갑시다.
He really has a killer smile.
그는 정말 살인적인 미소를 가지고 있습니다.
Judge Lee, please let us take a photo of you.
이 판사님, 받아주세요 당신의 사진.
- Any word for the bereaved? - Look this way!
- 유족들에게 전할 말은요? - 이쪽을 보세요!
It's her! Kang Ju-yeong.
그녀야! 강주영.
It's the kimchi fridge.
김치냉장고 입니다.
Kim Sang-jin's third victim was found in a kimchi fridge
김상진 세 번째 피해자 발견 김치 냉장고에
for a horrifying reason.
끔찍한 이유로.
I was dispatched to fix the air conditioner
나는 파견되었다 에어컨 고치려고
in the main bedroom
메인 침실에서
and the kimchi fridge was blocking the outdoor unit.
김치 냉장고가 막혔어요 실외기.
So, I tried to push it a bit to the side
그래서 살짝 옆으로 밀어보려고 했는데
- and the woman freaked out. - Why won't it move?
- 그리고 그 여자는 겁에 질렸습니다. - Why won't it move?
- What's inside that it's so heavy? - And
- 안에 뭐가 있는데 이렇게 무겁나요? - 그리고
it was odd to see the fridge
냉장고를 보니 이상했다
- in their bedroom. - Please don't touch this.
- 침실에서. - 이거 만지지 마세요.
She made such a big deal about it
그녀는 그것에 대해 정말 큰 일을 했어요
so I got curious.
그래서 궁금해졌습니다.
So, when she went to the bathroom
그래서 그 사람이 화장실에 갔을 때
I secretly opened it.
몰래 열어봤습니다.
I was mortified.
나는 창피했다.
What?
무엇?
Hey!
여기요!
Ha-yeon!
하연!
Did you have fun?
재미있게 보내셨나요?
Ha-yeon, let's eat dinner at home
하연아 저녁은 집에서 먹자
and come back out to play.
그리고 다시 놀러 오세요.
- Okay, Mommy. - Shake your hands off.
- 알았어, 엄마. - 손을 떼세요.
Don't forget your things.
당신의 물건을 잊지 마세요.
Let's go. Hold my hand.
갑시다. 내 손을 잡아요.
Let's go. Good girl.
갑시다. 좋은 여자.
Look at it.
보세요.
This car comes at a used car price
이 차는 중고차 가격으로 나옵니다
but it's as good as new.
하지만 새것이나 다름없어요.
There's a scratch.
긁힌 자국이 있어요.
I mean, it's almost new.
즉, 거의 새것입니다.
Please put in a good word for me
나한테 좋은 말 좀 해주세요.
to Jeong-ho, the angel.
천사 정호에게.
- Sure. - Thanks.
- 확신하는. - 감사해요.
ILJJA MART
일자마트
Hello.
안녕하세요.
Oh, hello.
아, 안녕하세요.
Could I ask you a question?
질문 하나 해도 될까요?
- Sure. - Has anyone
- 확신하는. - 누구 있어요?
come by to buy these in bulk?
이거 대량으로 사러 오시나요?
Oh...
아...
I'm not sure.
잘 모르겠습니다.
What do they look like?
그들은 어떻게 생겼나요?
She had a hat on, so I'm not sure. It was a woman.
그녀는 모자를 쓰고 있어서 잘 모르겠습니다. 여자였습니다.
I'm not sure.
잘 모르겠습니다.
This is the brand.
이것이 브랜드입니다.
We don't carry that.
우리는 그것을 가지고 있지 않습니다.
- Okay, then. - Have a good day.
- 그럼요. - 좋은 하루 보내세요.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
- Hello, Prosecutor Park. - Hey.
- 안녕하세요, 박검사님. - 여기요.
Sang-jin won't move an inch out of his house.
상진이가 움직이지 않아요 그의 집에서 1인치 떨어진 곳.
Forget that.
잊어버리세요.
Yesterday's game wasn't a rerun.
어제 경기는 재경기가 아니었습니다.
How did you know?
어떻게 알았나요?
And it goes all the way to the left!
그리고 왼쪽으로 쭉 갑니다!
And it keeps going!
그리고 그것은 계속됩니다!
Yes!
예!
- Huh? - Another home run!
- 뭐? - 또 홈런!
I was just stating my hope. I guessed.
나는 단지 희망을 말한 것뿐이었다. 나는 짐작했다.
Anyway, don't lose sight of Sang-jin.
어쨌든 상진을 놓치지 마세요.
Because that match made me become an Eagles fan.
그 시합이 날 이렇게 만들었으니까 이글스 팬입니다.
We're leaving tonight. Get ready.
우리는 오늘 밤에 떠날 예정이다. 준비하세요.
DALLAE APARTMENT
달래아파트
Sang-jin is outside.
상진이가 밖에 있어요.
Kim Sang-jin is a serial killer.
김상진은 연쇄살인범이다.
He'll kill a six-year-old girl today...
그는 오늘 여섯 살짜리 소녀를 죽일 것이다...
No.
아니요.
I can't let the kid die again.
그 아이를 다시 죽게 놔둘 수는 없어요.
KIM SANG-JIN IS A SERIAL KILLER
김상진은 연쇄살인범이다
Excuse me!
실례합니다!
There was a woman who bought loads of something else.
구매한 여자가 있었는데 다른 것들도 잔뜩.
- Ms. Kang Ju-yeong. - She almost became Kim's third target.
- 강주영 씨. - 그녀는 김씨의 세 번째 표적이 될 뻔했다.
I know you're being blackmailed by Mr. Kim Sang-jin.
당신이 협박당하고 있는 걸 알아요 김상진 선생님.
Another victim.
또 다른 피해자.
Ms. Kang.
강씨.
I know it all.
나는 그것을 모두 알고 있습니다.
You have no choice but to obey him
그에게 순종하는 것 외에는 다른 선택이 없습니다
because he's threatening to kill
죽이겠다고 위협하니까
your mother and niece working at the market.
네 엄마와 조카 시장에서 일해요.
I'm so sorry.
정말 죄송해요.
- Please forgive me. - Please open the door.
- 용서해주세요. - 문을 열어주세요.
I'm so sorry.
정말 죄송해요.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
It's okay.
괜찮아요.
You'll be okay.
괜찮을 거예요.
I should've died then.
그때 죽었어야 했는데.
I should've let him kill me.
그 사람이 나를 죽게 두었어야 했는데.
I should've died!
난 죽었어야 했는데!
What's wrong? Are you okay?
무슨 일이야? 괜찮으세요?
Please save me.
저를 구해주세요.
Hold on.
기다리다.
Your Honor
재판장님
please give me the death penalty.
저에게 사형을 선고해주세요.
I deserve to die.
나는 죽을 자격이 있습니다.
No, why should you die?
아니, 왜 죽어야 해?
You sentenced him to the death penalty
당신은 그에게 사형을 선고했습니다
but you let him out.
하지만 당신은 그를 내보내줬어요.
Why did you do that?
왜 그랬어요?
Why did you lie?
왜 거짓말을 했어요?
Now, he'll kill my mom and niece, too.
이제 그 사람은 우리 엄마와 조카도 죽일 거예요.
I didn't lie.
나는 거짓말을 하지 않았습니다.
I let him go to get him for good.
나는 그를 영원히 데려가려고 그를 놓아주었습니다.
To arrest him for murder charges
그를 살인 혐의로 체포하기 위해
instead of mere housebreaking.
단순한 집안일 대신.
So
그래서
trust me.
나를 믿으세요.
- Ye-na. - Yes?
- 예나. - 예?
It's dinnertime.
저녁 시간이에요.
- Hey, come on. - Hurry.
- 이봐, 어서. - 서두르다.
Sang-jin is at a nearby playground.
상진이는 근처 놀이터에 있어요.
I'm done after this.
이 후에는 끝났습니다.
- As for the rest... - Arrest him right now.
- 나머지는... - 지금 당장 체포하세요.
You're kidding!
농담이군요!
Have you gone mad?
화났어?
For what do I arrest a man
내가 무엇 때문에 사람을 체포합니까?
just eating snacks at a park?
그냥 공원에서 간식을 먹나요?
Did you not see my text?
내 문자 못 봤어?
Yeah, about him being a serial killer.
응, 그 사람이 연쇄 살인범이라는 얘기야.
Are you still onto that?
아직도 그 일을 하고 있나요?
There's a girl in a duck shirt
오리 셔츠를 입은 소녀가 있어요
at the playground, right?
놀이터에서요, 그렇죠?
How did you know?
어떻게 알았나요?
Where are you?
어디세요?
Arrest him right now.
지금 당장 그를 체포하세요.
Or she'll die.
아니면 그녀는 죽을 것이다.
What nonsense are you...
무슨 말도 안되는 소리야?
saying?
말하는거야?
He called me.
그는 나에게 전화했다.
Don't worry.
괜찮아요.
I'll make sure he can never call you again.
내가 확실히 할게 그 사람은 다시는 너한테 전화할 수 없어.
Did you arrest him?
그를 체포했나요?
He seemed to be on his phone
그 사람은 휴대폰을 하고 있는 것 같았어요
and suddenly ran away.
그리고 갑자기 도망쳤어요.
I'm chasing after him, but are you sure he's a murderer?
나는 그를 쫓고 있다. 그런데 그 사람이 살인자라는 게 확실해요?
Don't let him go. Get him, no matter what.
그를 놓아주지 마세요. 무슨 일이 있어도 그를 잡아라.
Fine.
괜찮은.
Are there spy cams here?
여기 스파이캠이 있나요?
The teddy!
테디!
I forgot
나는 잊었다
that he'd openly installed spy cams
그가 공개적으로 스파이 캠을 설치했다는 것
to threaten Kang Ju-yeong.
강주영을 위협한다.
Where are you right now?
지금 어디 계시나요?
A very steep set of stairs.
매우 가파른 계단입니다.
And now?
그리고 지금은?
On my way down after reaching the top.
정상에 도달한 후 내려가는 중.
Do you know where he is?
그 사람이 어디 있는지 아시나요?
He's going to kill my mom and niece.
그 사람은 우리 엄마와 조카를 죽일 거예요.
Please, sir.
부탁드립니다.
I have to see my mom.
엄마를 만나야 해요.
Please let me go to my mom!
엄마한테 가게 해주세요!
That's right. I'm a judge.
좋아요. 나는 판사입니다.
So
그래서
let's put Sang-jin on trial together.
상진이를 함께 재판에 회부시키자.
So that he can never mess with your mother or niece.
그 사람이 절대 엉망이 되지 않도록 어머니나 조카와 함께.
Do you know the way down?
내려가는 길을 아시나요?
Ju-yeong, repeat it out loud after me.
주영아, 나 따라 크게 따라해봐.
The court sentences the murderer, Kim Sang-jin...
법원의 선고 살인자 김상진...
"The court sentences the murderer, Kim Sang-jin..."
"법원이 선고 살인자 김상진..."
The court sentences the murderer, Kim Sang-jin!
법원의 선고 살인자 김상진!
Say it louder!
더 크게 말해보세요!
The court sentences the murderer, Kim Sang-jin!
법원의 선고 살인자 김상진!
Even louder!
더 크게!
The court sentences the murderer, Kim Sang-jin!
법원의 선고 살인자 김상진!
To death!
죽음에!
So ordered!
그래서 주문했습니다!
THE JUDGE RETURNS
판사가 돌아오다
A judge shouldn't do this.
판사는 이런 짓을 해서는 안 된다.
Do I have to be nice, too?
나도 친절해야 하나?
Whatever it is
그것이 무엇이든
don't you know all court decisions are recorded?
모르시나요? 모든 법원 판결은 기록되나요?
I hear there's an interesting judge at the Chungnam Court.
재미있는 판사가 있다고 들었는데 충남법원에서.
Find a case and assign it to Judge Lee.
사건을 찾아 이 판사에게 배정하세요.
A bride-to-be died in a car accident.
예비 신부가 교통사고로 사망했습니다.
At first, I thought it was an accident.
처음에는 사고인 줄 알았습니다.
The issue is, all her insurances had
문제는 그녀의 모든 보험이
an assigned beneficiary.
지정된 수혜자.
Bring my Seong-hui back to life!
내 성희를 다시 살려내세요!
Do your job! You're a judge!
일을 하세요! 당신은 판사입니다!
Do you think Park Hyeok-jun really did it?
정말 박혁준이 그랬다고 생각하시나요?
Success ends quickly without a good leader.
성공은 빨리 끝난다 좋은 리더가 없으면.
Who are you, really?
당신은 정말로 누구입니까?
Are you a real judge?
당신이 진짜 판사인가요?
Subtitles by Min-sun Kim
자막: 김민선